Finding Aid for the Morton Feldman Papers, 1950-1999
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Morton Feldman Papers, 1950-1999
Mus. Arc. 2.1
Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987
16 boxes
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The Morton Feldman Papers comprise personal and business correspondence, writings by and about Feldman, clippings, programs, and photographs.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
The bulk of the material was received as a gift from Barbara Monk Feldman in 1992. Additional photographs were donated by William M. Colleran. Some clippings and programs were added by Music Library staff subsequent to the receipt of the collection.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
Photographs in the collection have been digitized and are available in University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.
Biographical Note
Composer Morton Feldman (1926-1987) was best known for his association with the New York School of experimentalist musicians, including composers John Cage, Christian Wolff, and Earle Brown, and pianist David Tudor. In addition to composing approximately 150 works, Feldman also wrote more than three dozen articles about various aspects of music and art.
Feldman was a member of the music department faculty at the State University of New York at Buffalo from 1972-1987. During those years he served as Slee Professor of Music 1972-1973, Edgar Varèse Professor 1975-1987, and Director of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts, 1976-1980. He was also responsible for creating the June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music in 1975.
Scope and Content Note
The Morton Feldman Papers consist predominantly of secondary materials, including eight boxes of programs and clippings, two boxes of Feldman's published writings, and another box of writings for or about Feldman. Other than a small number of musical fragments, it contains none of Feldman's scores, printed or manuscript.
There are two prose manuscripts and six typescripts by Feldman in the collection. These are primarily brief (the longest is 5 leaves) and fragmentary in nature. Feldman's published writings are represented by thirty-two articles in the collection. The list includes articles translated into German, Swedish, Italian, and French. Eighteen interviews and conversations with Feldman are also included in the collection, almost all of them available in published versions.
The correspondence in the Morton Feldman Papers reveals little of a personal nature about Feldman. The letters in the fifty-three folders of General Correspondence include letters of appreciation from students, invitations to appear at functions, letters regarding details of upcoming events, and letters of thanks from presenters of concerts and lectures.
There are only three letters from Feldman included in the General Correspondence. They are filed by name of the addressee. One of these, a photocopy of a letter sent to soprano Joan La Barbara along with the score of Feldman's composition Three Voices, is perhaps the only letter in the collection with any musical content. Feldman's other two letters were to University at Buffalo colleagues, James Coover and Maria Runfola.
There are an additional eleven folders of correspondence related to awards received by Feldman, commissions, contracts for appearances, and royalty statements. Feldman served as a consultant for the Mark Rothko Foundation's Mark Rothko Fund, which granted funds to older artists, writers, and musicians. Correspondence received from applicants with backgrounds in music was sent to Feldman for his recommendation. The correspondence is addressed to the treasurer of the foundation, Bernard J. Reis.
There are more than five hundred programs and announcements in the collection and approximately four hundred clippings and reviews. Together these provide substantial documentation of Feldman's career and the critical reception of his music. The collection of sixty-one photographs contains candid snapshots, as well as some formal portraits of Feldman taken while he was at Darmstadt in 1986.
The principal collection of material related to the life and career of Morton Feldman is located at the Paul Sacher Stiftung in Basel, Switzerland.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in eleven series.
I. Personal documents
II. Manuscripts and typescripts
A. Writings by Feldman
B. Musical fragments
III. Printed articles by Feldman
IV. Feldman interviews and conversations
V. Writings for, or about, Feldman
VI. Subject files
VII. Correspondence
A. General
B. Awards
C. Business: contracts, royalties, commissions, and publishing
D. Mark Rothko Foundation
E. Student papers
VIII. Programs and announcements
IX. Clippings
X. Photographs
XI. Oversize
Container List
- Personal documents, 1961-1985, I.; Folders 1-4
  In original order.
  - Vita, circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vita, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Travel vouchers, June 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Voter registration card, New York City, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Manuscripts and typescripts, circa 1950-1985, II.; Folders 5-16
  Musical and prose manuscripts and typescripts.
  - Writings by Feldman, circa 1950-1985, II.A; Folders 5-15
    Two manuscript and six typescript writings by Feldman, chiefly fragmentary. A transcription of all the writings, with the exception of one typescript, is included.
    - Manuscript 1: Piano and Voices II was written ..., undated, 5 leaves; Title from first line of text. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript 2: The first enthusiastic mention of G.S. [Giacinto Scelsi] ..., undated, 1 leaf; Title from first line of text. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Typescript 1: Sound, noise, Varèse, Boulez, circa 1958, 2 leaves; Published In It Is, 1958. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Typescript 2: I can't say that in terms of fame ..., undated, 1 leaf; Title from first line of text, which begins on p. 2. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Typescript 3: Mid-way, undated, 2 leaves; First line of text: "I am writing this at mid-career ..." (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Typescript 4: Jackson Pollock, undated, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Typescript 5: This is not in the nature of an apology ..., undated, 1 leaf; Title from first line of text. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Typescript 6: Aphorisms, undated, 3 leaves (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Typescript 7: What is so characteristic of the 20th century is that Hindemuth [sic]..., undated, 1 leaf; Title from first line of text. (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    - Transcriptions by Sebastian Claren of all but Typescript 1 above (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Quotations from Hart Crane and Rameau in Feldman's hand (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Typescript and manuscript Ph.D. examination questions for four students at the State University of New York at Buffalo (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Musical fragments, undated, II.B; Folders 16a-16e
    Five musical fragments in holograph.
    - Unheard footfalls only sound, undated, 1 leaf; Sketch for what became a section of Feldman's composition, Neither. (Box 1, Folder 16a)
      Includes 1 reproduction on heavier paper.
    - Untitled graphically-notated score fragment for "Brass, Woodwinds and Metal", undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 16b)
    - Untitled sketches: Side A: dated Sept. 7/56; single-line melody. Side B: two staves, d minor triad arpeggio repeated in left hand, 1956, 1 leaf music paper with music on both sides, in pencil (Box 1, Folder 16c)
    - Followe Thy Faire Sunne, for voice and chimes, 1962, 1 leaf, in pencil; Text by Thomas Campion. Unpublished work; Fair copy in Paul Sacher Stiftung has slightly different ending. (Box 1, Folder 16d)
    - Untitled pencil manuscript, possibly for violin and piano 1957, 1 leaf; On verso: handwritten information about "All Feldman concert, Jan. 1, 1957 Projections, Intersections". (Box 1, Folder 16e)
- Printed articles by Morton Feldman, 1951-1997, III.; Folders 17-53
  The folders are alphabetically arranged by article title. Where an article appears in a foreign translation, it is filed under the English title, followed by the language of the translation. Additional program notes written by Feldman can be found in Series VIII, Programs and Announcements.
  - After Modernism, February 1967, Published In Six Painters: Mondrian, Guston, Kline, De Kooning, Pollock, Rothko: Houston, Texas, February-April 1967, University of St. Thomas Art Department: 14-22 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Anxiety of Art, 1973, Published In Art in America, v. 61, n. 5 (September-October 1973): 88-93 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Anxiety of Art. German Angst vor der Kunst, 1997, Published In Gütersloh '97: für Morton Feldman [program book]: 29-34. The program book also contains Feldman's articles: Strawinsky and Über Stefan Wolpe. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Anxiety of Art. Swedish Konstens ängslan, 1968-1969, Published In Nutida Musik, v. 12, n. 3 (1968/69): 36-41 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Between categories, 1973, Published In Mundus Artium, v. 6, n. 1 (1973): p. 94-98 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Between categories. French Entre des catégories, 1970, Published In Musique en jeu, v. 1? 1970?: 22-26 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Between categories. Swedish Mellan kategorierna, 1968-1969, Published In Nutida Musik, v. 12, n. 4 (1968/69): 25-27 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Boola Boola, 1966-1967, Published In Composer (Composers Guild of Britain), n. 22 (Winter 1966/67): 13-16 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Contemporary Music Catalogue, August 12, 1975, Edition Peters, 1975. p. 32. Facsimile of one paragraph holograph of Feldman's stating why he no longer wrote about music. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Crippled symmetry, 1981, Published In Res, 2 (Autumn 1981): 91-103 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Earle Brown, 1966, Universal Edition pamphlet, 1 page. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Essay [on Philip Guston], 1980, Published In Philip Guston, 1980: the last works: organized by the Phillips Collection: 5-8 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Essay [on Philip Guston]. German Essay, 1996, Published In Morton Feldman zum 70. Geburtstag: For Philip Guston: Sonntag, 21. Januar 1996 in der Berlinischen Galerie, Martin-Gropius-Bau: 16-20 Includes articles about Feldman. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - False relationships (Swedish), 1969-1970, Published In Nutida Musik, v. 13, n. 2 (1969/70): 16 (1 paragraph) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - In Memoriam: Edgard Varèse (1883-1965), 1966, Published In Perspectives of New Music, v. 4, n. 2 (Spring-Summer 1966): 12 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - In Memoriam: Edgard Varèse (1883-1965). German, 1988, Published In Positionen der Moderne: Drei Konzerte, Berlinische Galerie, Museum für Moderne Künst, Photographie und Architektur: 12., 13. und 14. Februar 1988, Martin-Gropius-Bau: 13 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - In Memoriam: Edgard Varèse (1883-1965). Swedish, 1967-1968, Published In Nutida Musik, v. 11, n. 5-6 (1967/68): 46-47. The issue also contains Feldman's article, Varken eller ( Neither - Nor. Swedish (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Internationale Ferienkurse für Neue Musik Darmstadt 1986: Komponistenforum Morton Feldman, 24. 7. 1986, Lecture, parts missing. Transcription by Sebastian Claren, 1993. 10 p. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - John de Menil (1904-1973), 1973, Published In Art in America, v. 61, n. 6 (Nov.-Dec. 1973): 41 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - June in Buffalo lecture, Tuesday 17 June 1986, Beginning of lecture missing. Transcription by Sebastian Claren, 1993. 11 p. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Letter to the editor of Art News, April 1954, Published In Art News, v. 53, n. 2 (April 1954): 6. One paragraph and editor's response. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - A Life without Bach or Beethoven, 1964, Published In Listen: a music monthly (May-June 1964): 14 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Life without Bach or Beethoven. Italian Una vita senza Bach e Beethoven, 1969, Published In Lo Spettatore Musicale (March 1969): 2-4 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Liner notes written for Time/Life recording, Feldman/Brown (58007/S), 1963. 1962, Published In Kulchur, v. 2, n. 6 (Summer 1962): 57-60 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Marginal Intersection (1951), Intersection 2 (1951), Intermission 6 (for one or two pianos)[brief program notes followed by graphically notated scores.], 1963, Published In Kulchur, v. 3, n. 11 (Autumn 1963): p. 33-36 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Middelburg lecture July 2, 1985, Published In The First Middelburg lecture. "The present text is an edited and annotated transcription of a lecture given by Morton Feldman on Tuesday, July 2, 1985 at De Kloveniersdoelen, Middelburg, The Netherlands." Edited and annotated by Paul van Emmerik, Vincent Gasseling and Michael Nieuwenhuizen. Photocopy from unidentified source: 5-12. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Middelburg lecture July 2, 1987, Feldman lecture (in English). Transcription of a lecture and question/answer period with audience at Middelburg Festival Nieuwe Muziek, July 2, 1987. Edited by Michael Nieuwenhuizen, Vincent Gasseling and Paul van Emmerik. Published in: Morton Feldman retrospectieff: Programmaboek: Voices an instruments: 22 tot en met 27 Januari 1991, Groningen: 13-21 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Middelburg lecture July 2, 1987, "The text printed below is an excerpt (a lecture given by Feldman on Thursday morning, July 2, 1987 in De Kloveniersdoelen, Middelburg, The Netherlands) of the complete lectures given by Feldman during his masterclasses as part of the Festival Nieuwe Muziek in 1985, 1986, and 1987, transcribed, edited and annotated by Paul van Emmerik, Vincent Gasseling and Michael Nieuwenhuizen and to be published by Stichtung Nieuwe Muziek Zeeland in 1988." 12 p. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Mr. Schuller's History Lesson: [Review of concert at Carnegie Hall, Nov. 9, 1962, conducted by Gunther Schuller], 1963, Published In Kulchur, v. 3, n. 9 (Spring 1963): 88-89 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Morton Feldman über Morton Feldman, 1989, Program notes for May 31, 1989 concert at the Ballhaus Naunystrasse, Berlin. p. [4] (approximately 4 paragraphs long) Note: Contains facsimile reproduction of the manuscript score of Feldman's Trio for Flutes (March 5, 1972) (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Neither - Nor. German Weder/Noch, (1968), Published In Dialog: Musik: Vier Konzerte in der Berlinischen Galerie: Museum für Moderne Künst, Photographie und Architektur: 1. bis 3. Dezember 1989, Martin-Gropius-Bau: 42-44 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Neither - Nor. Swedish Varken eller, 1967-1968, Published In Nutida Musik, v. 11, n. 5/6 (1967/68): 45-46. Issue also contains Feldman's article, In Memoriam: Edgard Varèse (1883-1965). Swedish (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 4 musicians at work: Morton Feldman. [Projections and Intersections], 1952, Published In Trans Formation, v. 1, n. 3 (1952): 168 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Some Elementary Questions, 1967, Published In Art in America, v. 66, n. 2 (April 1967): 54-55 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Sound, noise, Varèse and Boulez, 1958, Published In It is, n. 2 (Autumn 1958): 46 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Strawinsky, 1997, Published In Gütersloh '97: für Morton Feldman [program book]: 14-16. The program book also contains Feldman's articles: Angst vor der Kunst and Über Stefan Wolpe. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Swallows of Salangan program notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Twelve tone tech[n]ique in Varèse's Déserts: Thurs. 26, Feb. 1981, CalArts, Lecture. Transcription by Sebastian Claren, 1993. 14 p. (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - über Stefan Wolpe, 1997, Published In Gütersloh '97: für Morton Feldman [program book]: 21. The program book also contains Feldman's articles: Angst vor der Kunst and Strawinsky. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Vertical thoughts, 1963, Published In Kulchur, v. 3, n. 11 (Autumn 1963): p. 37-38 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Feldman interviews and conversations, 1964-1987, IV.; Folders 54-71
  Transcriptions of seventeen interviews or conversations with Morton Feldman.
  The folders are alphabetically arranged by name of the interviewer and then alphabetically by title.
  - Ashley, Robert Part of an interview with Morton Feldman, August, 1964, In Kulchur, v. 5, n. 18 (Summer 1965): p. 20-24. (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Beckett, Alan Feldman/Beckett, 1966, 15 typescript leaves; Published as "Morton Feldman" In The International Times, v. 3 (Nov. 14-27, 1966); also In Some of IT, edited by David Mairowitz, London: Knullar, 1969., v. 5, n. 18 (Summer 1965): p. 20-24. (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Borradori, Giovanni Una liaison tra Webern e Cage: conversazione con Morton Feldman, April 1986, In Musica/Realtà, anno 7, n. 19 (April 1986): 53-66 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Bortolotto, Mario Intervista con Morton Feldman, January 1969, In Lo Spettatore Musicale (January 24?, 1969): 10-13 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Cage, John Conversation with Morton Feldman, 1983, In Res, 6 (Autumn 1983): 113-135 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Cage, John John Cage-Morton Feldman: a radio conversation broadcast in New York, introduced by Michael Chanan, 1967, In Circuit 4, v. 2, n. 6 (Spring-Summer 1967): 3-11 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Cage, John John Cage und Morton Feldman ... tief in Gedanken: Radiogespräch vom 9 July 1966, In Gütersloh '95/96: Morton Feldman, Kazuo Fukushima, Walter Zimmermann Portraits: Drei Kammerkonzerte im Theater der Stadt Gütersloh: 8-14. First printed In Musiktexte 45 (1992) (Box 3, Folder 60)
    Includes articles about Feldman.
  - Dwyer, John I met Heine on the Rue Furstenburg, 23 April 1973, In Buffalo Evening News, Saturday April 21, 1973: B6 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    Feldman in conversation with John Dwyer.
  - Frost, Everett Interview with Morton Feldman, 10 March 1987: after recording Beckett, Words and Music., 10 pages; Transcription copyrighted by Sebastian Claren, 1993. (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Griffiths, Paul Morton Feldman talks to Paul Griffiths, August 1972, In The Musical Times, v. 113, n. 1554 (August 1972): 758-759 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Laycock, Jolyon, and David Charlton An interview with Morton Feldman at Nottingham University, May 1966, In Opus 2, v. 1, n. 6? (Spring 1967): 18-20. (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Orton, Fred, and Gavin Bryars Morton Feldman, May 27, 1976, London, 5 photocopied leaves (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Rizzardi, Venerio Segue dibattito con l'autore: in un colloquio con una decina di spettatori Morton Feldman parla didiverse cose: musica e arti visive, distanze e vicinanze nelle esperienze americane di oggi, December 1979, In Scena, v. 4, n. 5-6 (December 1979): 52-53 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Unidentified interviewer. Conversations without Stravinsky, March 1967, In London Magazine, v. 6, n. 12 (March 1967): 86-94 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    "An abstract of several informal talks in New York between the American avant-garde composer Morton Feldman and a friend."
  - Williams, Jan, 1939 An interview with Morton Feldman, September 1983, In Percussive Notes, v. 21, n. 6 (Sept. 1983): 4-14 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001 In conversation: Morton Feldman and Iannis Xenakis, April 1987. Edited by Vincent Gasseling and Michael Nieuwenhuizen., In Centrum Nieuwe Muziek (Middelburg)(April 1987): 6-11 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Young, La Monte A conversation on composition and improvisation, 1987, In Res, 13 (Spring 1987)153-173 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Zimmermann, Walter Att behålla kontrollen över tystnaden: samtal mellan Morton Feldman och Walter Zimmermann, 1988-1989, In Nutida Musik, v. 32, n. 4 (1988/89): 22-29 (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Writings for, or about, Feldman, 1964/1997, V.; Folders 72-88
  The series includes a small number of unpublished writings, including Brian O'Doherty's eulogy for Feldman, an unidentified poem dedicated to Feldman, and some typescript notes by Barney Childs about Feldman's music. Additional writings about Feldman are located in Series VIII, Programs and Announcements and Series IX, Clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Ashton, Dore Correspondent's report from New York, January 1964, Canadian Art, v. 21 (Jan. 1964): p. 48 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Bortolotto, Mario Di Feldman e d'altre cose, December 1970, Lo Spettatore Musicale, Dec. 1970: p. 17-19. (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Childs, Barney Notes about Feldman's music, undated, Photocopy of typescript (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Dean, Samantha Morton Feldman, undated, Buffalo Spree, no date: p. 54-57. (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Emmerik, Paul van Chronologisches Werkverzeichnis; Bibliographie, 1986, Published as the Musik-Konzepte title, Morton Feldman (Musik-Konzepte Heft 48/49: p. 154-183) (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Erdmann, Martin Traumbruchstücke, unvermittelt: Neue Kammermusik und Essays von Morton Feldman January 1987, Neue Zeitschrift für Musik, 148. Jahrgang, Heft 1 (January 1987): p. 18-21 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Gronemeyer, Gisela Momennte von grosser Schünheit: zu Morton Feldmans neuem Stück Crippled Symmetry April 1984, In MusikTexte, April 1984, Heft 4: p. 5-9 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Gruhn, Wilfried Klang und Stille: Gedanken zur kompositorischen Arbeit Morton Feldmans March 1982, In Musik und Bildung, 14. Jahrgang (73.), Heft 3 (March 1982): p. 147-152 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - O'Doherty, Brian Feldman Eulogy, September 9, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - O'Doherty, Brian Untitled typescript notes about Feldman's music, 1971, These notes were printed as part of the liner notes for the CRI SD 276 recording (1971?) of Feldman's The Viola in My Life and False Relationships and the Extended Ending (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Schiavo, Paul Words and Music: Feldman at sixty: Review of Morton Feldman Essays, 1986, In American Book Review, Jan.-Feb. 1986?, p. 5-6 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Straebel, Volker Some reflections on Morton Feldman 1997, Peters Notes, Winter 1997, v. 2, n. 1: p. 5, 7 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
    Bibliography
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
    Poem titled Hammer Wing for Morton Feldman
  - De Vos Malan, Jacques Musical examples identified as being part of An Analysis of Morton Feldman's Work "Rothko Chapel" 1984 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Van Rossum, Frans Portret van componist Morton Feldman May 1986, Muziek & Dans, May 1986, 10e jaargang, n. 5/6: p. 10-14 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Zimmermann, Walter Morton Feldman, der Ikonoklast: Trio (1980) April 1984, Melos, 46. Jahrgang, 4 (April 1984): p. 33-75 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    Includes works list.
- Subject files, circa 1950-1987, VI.; Folders 89-98
  Programs, clippings, and articles collected by Feldman.
  Alphabetically arranged by name of subject.
  - People, circa 1950-1985, VI.A; Folders 89-95
    - Cage, John, 1951-1972, 4 items (Box 4, Folder 89)
      1951
      Cage's article A few ideas about music and film, in Film music notes, 10:3: p. 12-15.
      1958
      Program and program notes for A retrospective concert of twenty-five years of the music of John Cage, May 15, [1958], Town Hall, New York, N.Y.
      1964
      Calvin Tomkins's article, Figure in an imaginary landscape, in The New Yorker, Nov. 28, 1964. Incomplete
      1972
      Cover photograph of John Cage for Records and recording, August 1972.
    - Guston, Philip, 1913-1980, 1960-1987, 6 items (Box 4, Folder 90)
      1960
      Exhibition catalog: Sidney Janis presents an exhibition of recent paintings by Guston, December 28, 1959-January 23, 1960, Sidney Janis Gallery, New York, N.Y.
      1970
      Program for Centennial convocation honoring Philip Guston, Boston University School of Fine and Applied Arts, March 12, 1970. Feldman listed to introduce Guston.
      1980
      Invitation from the SCM Corporation and Corcoran Gallery of Art to attend opening of a retrospective of Philip Guston, July 18, 1980
      1981
      Invitation to exhibition, Philip Guston: the last works, March 20, 1981, Phillips Collection, Washington, D.C.
      Invitation to exhibition, Philip Guston, July 1, 1981, Whitney Museum, New York, N.Y.
      1987